<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title><![CDATA[TobyG.net]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.tobyg.net/blog/categories/about me.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://blog.tobyg.net/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-18T16:45:37+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.tobyg.net/</id>
        <generator uri="http://sculpin.io/">Sculpin</generator>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome - So what&#039;s this all about?]]></title>
            <link href="http://blog.tobyg.net/blog/2016/02/14/welcome-so-whats-this-all-about"/>
            <updated>2016-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
            <id>http://blog.tobyg.net/blog/2016/02/14/welcome-so-whats-this-all-about</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I've finally got round to doing what I said I was going to do, and get this blog back up and running again.  I've 
never really been one for writing, but over the last few years I've come to realise that the thoughts and knowledge in 
my head might actually be of use to a few other people.  I've also started to realise that I can have a positive effect 
on the world, if I want to, by sharing my thoughts an ideas with anyone who'd like to listen.</p>

<p>I think about a lot.  I'm passionate about a lot.  I'm also very aware that, whist I love the person I am today, I know 
that I will only ever be the best me I can be (in this existence, anyway) when I run out of time to learn anything more. 
So I thought I would share my journey, my lessons, my thoughts &amp; inspirations in the hope that they have a positive 
effect on anyone who cares to read them here in my new blog.</p>

<p>I was going to add a typical 'About me' page to this blog, but as someone very close to me suggests, surely the contents 
of each post I write in this blog is a far better way of finding out about who I am, so here is me… who I was, and who I 
am, and who I hope to become.</p>

<p>I hope you enjoy the read.</p>
]]></content>
        </entry>
    </feed>