<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title><![CDATA[TobyG.net]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.tobyg.net/blog/categories/random thoughts.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://blog.tobyg.net/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-29T11:37:40+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.tobyg.net/</id>
        <generator uri="http://sculpin.io/">Sculpin</generator>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is the cost of our convenience?]]></title>
            <link href="http://blog.tobyg.net/blog/2016/11/26/what-is-the-cost-of-our-convenience"/>
            <updated>2016-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
            <id>http://blog.tobyg.net/blog/2016/11/26/what-is-the-cost-of-our-convenience</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night, we put up our Christmas tree the earliest I think we've ever done it, to cheer ourselves up after missing 
our flight to France for the weekend. While we did we put on National Geographic's 
"<a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/70073731">Arctic Tale</a>", to add a little snow to the occasion. I thought it might help 
bring in the festive cheer a little... however, as the program continued following the lives of the animals of the 
Antarctic, and how they are all intertwined, it became more and more worrying about the fate of these wonderful 
creatures that share our lovely planet with us. Each year their hunting &amp; feeding gets harder &amp; harder as the ice flats 
where they rest and hunt become smaller &amp; smaller, and less &amp; less stable. They're having to swim longer &amp; further each 
summer just to be able to climb out of the ice cold water.</p>

<p>So we all know this is happening... we all know about global warming... and yet, despite this... despite the fact that 
these beautiful creatures are becoming more &amp; more endangered each year, we, as a society don't seem to be too bothered. 
Will we miss them when they're gone?</p>

<p>Despite all this though... there's plenty that could be done. We all can make a difference... but do we? Or is our 
lifestyle &amp; convenience worth more to us? Will it be out downfall? Whilst we all drive around in our fancy cars, 
guzzling fossil fuels, and adding to the greenhouse gases that are causing this worrying phenomenon, how many of us look 
for a more environmentally friendly option? How many of us actually consider sharing a lift to work, or on a long 
journey? How many of us would rather travel by public transport, in an attempt to reduce or carbon footprint. I know, 
for one, I'm guilty of this to a certain extent. I know very few (but luckily some) people who do all they can to keep 
their impact to a minimum... but what will it take to make us, a society as a whole, change our view on these things? 
The extinction 100s of species on this planet? The ever increasing number of natural disasters? The knowledge that, if 
we don't do anything now, our existence as a species is in danger? Who knows? Do we care enough?</p>

<p>We've already switched over to a purely green energy supplier earlier this year, but now we've also decided to do a few 
more things to help reduce our impact on the planet.</p>

<p>A few quick wins... we've decided to wear jumpers a little more in the house, and reduce the length of time we have the 
heating on.  We're also going to make a point of keeping lids on cooking pots on the stove to help prevent unnecessary 
heat loss during cooking.</p>

<p>Long term, we're going to start research into installing solar panels &amp; a Tesla Powerwall (house battery, to store the 
solar generated power).  Whilst not a cheap outlay, we think it's worth it, to help move things in the right direction, 
even if they don't necessarily pay for themselves (which may still a good possibility).  I've also downloaded the 
<a href="https://www.blablacar.co.uk/">BlaBlaCar module app</a> to look at sharing my car journeys with other like minded people, 
having been told about it by a friend, just the other day.</p>

<p>Do you have any thoughts on this?  Have you made any concious decisions to reduce your impact on the environment?  Let 
me know in the comments below... or <a href="https://twitter.com/ToG">tweet me</a>.</p>

<p>If you do want to make a difference, hopefully the following links will help...</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://footprint.wwf.org.uk/">Carbon calculator</a></li>
<li><a href="https://liftshare.com/uk">Car sharing</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.energysavingtrust.org.uk/travel/driving-advice">How to drive more efficiently</a></li>
<li><a href="https://carbonfund.org/reduce/">Improve your energy efficiency</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.which.co.uk/reviews/solar-panels/article/guides">Solar panels</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.tesla.com/powerwall">Tesla house battery</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.ovoenergy.com/">Green energy providers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.tesla.com/">Tesla electric cars</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dentists - Why do I struggle to trust their advice?]]></title>
            <link href="http://blog.tobyg.net/blog/2016/02/18/dentists---why-do-i-struggle-to-trust-their-advice"/>
            <updated>2016-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
            <id>http://blog.tobyg.net/blog/2016/02/18/dentists---why-do-i-struggle-to-trust-their-advice</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I sometimes consider myself an advertisers worst target.  Unless they catch me in just the right mood, at just the right 
time with something that I already kind of like or want, then their efforts are actually more likely to put me off 
buying their products.</p>

<p>So when I went to the dentist the other day, and I'm sat in the waiting room, surrounded by posters for this toothpaste, 
mouthwash and teeth whitening offerings, it got me thinking… I go to the dentist to make sure I have health teeth. I 
trust the knowledge and skill of my dentist to perform this 6 monthly oral MOT and keep things running as they should… 
but when it comes to the end of my appointment, I always receive a recommendation for a new toothbrush, tooth paste or 
mouthwash. Now I accept I'm not the best at cleaning my teeth, so some extra help is needed, but when they then proceed 
to produce a pre-printed pad showing all the oral toothbrush options, and another for Listerene mouthwashes, to tick and 
hand to me, it's difficult to believe that they're giving me the best advice tor me, rather than the financial benefit 
of their business.</p>

<p>I wondered whether the Colgate branded "Leading Practice award" in reception was a recognition of excellence in 
dentistry? Or, as as my thoughts questioned, for selling a load of Colgate products?</p>

<p>Don't get me wrong, I appreciate, as a business owner myself, that businesses have to make a profit, but it's difficult 
in a world were advertising is everywhere, who do you trust? Am I just a lone sceptic in an otherwise accepting world?</p>
]]></content>
        </entry>
    </feed>