<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title><![CDATA[TobyG.net]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.tobyg.net/blog/categories/the environment.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://blog.tobyg.net/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-27T19:43:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.tobyg.net/</id>
        <generator uri="http://sculpin.io/">Sculpin</generator>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is the cost of our convenience?]]></title>
            <link href="http://blog.tobyg.net/blog/2016/11/26/what-is-the-cost-of-our-convenience"/>
            <updated>2016-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
            <id>http://blog.tobyg.net/blog/2016/11/26/what-is-the-cost-of-our-convenience</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night, we put up our Christmas tree the earliest I think we've ever done it, to cheer ourselves up after missing 
our flight to France for the weekend. While we did we put on National Geographic's "<a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/70073731">Arctic Tale</a>", to add a little 
snow to the occasion. I thought it might help bring in the festive cheer a little… however, as the program continued 
following the lives of the animals of the Antarctic, and how they are all intertwined, it became more and more worrying 
about the fate of these wonderful creatures that share our lovely planet with us. Each year their hunting &amp; feeding gets 
harder &amp; harder as the ice flats where they rest and hunt become smaller &amp; smaller, and less &amp; less stable. They're 
having to swim longer &amp; further each summer just to be able to climb out of the ice cold water.
So we all know this is happening… we all know about global warming… and yet, despite this… despite the fact that these 
beautiful creatures are becoming more &amp; more endangered each year, we, as a society don't seem to be too bothered. Will 
we miss them when they're gone?</p>

<p>Despite all this though… there's plenty that could be done. We all can make a difference… but do we? Or is our lifestyle 
&amp; convenience worth more to us? Will it be out downfall? Whilst we all drive around in our fancy cars, guzzling fossil 
fuels, and adding to the greenhouse gases that are causing this worrying phenomenon, how many of us look for a more 
environmentally friendly option? How many of us actually consider sharing a lift to work, or on a long journey? How many 
of us would rather travel by public transport, in an attempt to reduce or carbon footprint. I know, for one, I'm guilty 
of this to a certain extent. I know very few (but luckily some) people who do all they can to keep their impact to a 
minimum… but what will it take to make us, a society as a whole, change our view on these things? The extinction 100s of 
species on this planet? The ever increasing number of natural disasters? The knowledge that, if we don't do anything 
now, our existence as a species is in danger? Who knows? Do we care enough?</p>

<p>Do you have any thoughts on this?  Let me know in the comments below… or <a href="https://twitter.com/ToG">tweet me</a></p>

<p>If you do want to make a difference, hopefully the following links will help…</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://footprint.wwf.org.uk/">Carbon calculator</a></li>
<li><a href="https://liftshare.com/uk">Car sharing</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.energysavingtrust.org.uk/travel/driving-advice">How to drive more efficiently</a></li>
<li><a href="https://carbonfund.org/reduce/">Improve your energy efficiency</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.which.co.uk/reviews/solar-panels/article/guides">Solar panels</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.tesla.com/powerwall">Tesla house battery</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.ovoenergy.com/">Green energy providers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.tesla.com/">Tesla electric cars</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </entry>
    </feed>